English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
Come, christians all, behold the lamb MS Eng 1507, John Webb: his book, 1777, 2nd following 26
Come, come away, come, come away MS Thr 198, folder 88
Come, come away to the Temple Hall MS Eng 834, folder 12
Come, come, it is at last agreed MS Eng 629, 30v
Come, come, my good shepherds, our flocks we must shear (incomplete) MS Eng 1038.1, 41
Come, come, oh come, confess to me MS Mus 237, i, 10
Come, come, ye jovial sportsmen all MS Eng 1038.1, 74v
Come, courage lads, and drink away MS Thr 198, folder 32
Come, cut again, the game's not done MS Eng 633, 66
Come (dearest Julia) thou and I MS Eng 631, 96
Come, dearest Lsoryelour, come away MS Eng 926, 82
Come, doleful muse, come help me to bemoan MS Eng 639, 7v
Come down, come down, my Lady Ogilvie (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 6
Come, Echo, I thee summon MS Eng 686, 82; MS Eng 540
Come, fair one, be kind, you never shall find, a fellow so fit for a lover MS Eng 1038.1, 27v
Come, fates, I fear you not, all whom I owe MS Eng 966.1, 36
Come, for the woodman's jaded arm gives o'er (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 93
Come forth thou unbaptized soul MS Eng 686, 15
Come, fierce resolves, take thou the van MS Eng 630, 9v
Come, gentle sleep, attend thy votary's prayer MS Keats 3.13, i, 37
Come, gentle Sylvia, and with pleasure view MS Eng 926, 23v
Come, gentlemen, let's up now (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 140v
Come hear my relations in deep lamentation MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 189
Come, hearties, work away MS Thr 198, folder 90
Come here, come here, you freely feed, and lay your head low on my knee MS Eng 1486 (2), 36
Come here, come here, ye freely feed MS Eng 1486 (1), 44
Come here, my sweet and pretty creature MS Eng 895, 87
Come here, ye afflicted, of ev'ry degree MS Eng 895, 3v
Come hither all sweet maidens, soberly MS Keats 3.2, 193; MS Keats 4.20.9,7; MS Keats 3.12, 66; MS Keats 2.12, 1
Come hither, good people, both aged and young MS Eng 1491 (3), 70v
Come hither, my boy, tell me what thou seest there MS Eng 1167, 52; MS Eng 889, 45
Come hither my country squire, take friendly instructions from me MS Eng 1038.1, 38
Come hither, my sparrows MS Eng 1167, 53
Come hither, read my gentle friend MS Eng 686, 10v
Come hither, Sir John, see, my picture is here MS Eng 1323, 69
Come hither you Tories and Jacobites now MS Eng 1143
Come, holy celestial dove MS Eng 614, 53v; MS Eng 616, ii, 44v
Come, Holy Ghost, all-quick'ning fire MS Eng 614, 125
Come, Holy Ghost, my soul inspire MS Eng 614, 130
Come, Holy Ghost, set to thy seal (incomplete) MS Eng 616, ii, 46
Come, Holy Ghost, thine influence shed MS Eng 616, ii, 46
Come, Holy Spirit, come MS Eng 616, ii, 38v
Come, honest sexton, take thy spade MS Eng 584, 39v
Come, Isaac, come, my boy, and let me see MS Eng 569.63, 33
Come kiss wi' me, come clap wi' me MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 170v
Come knock your heads against this stone MS Eng 1167, 19; MS Eng 889, 12
Come, ladies, shall we talk a round? as men (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Come, Laura, joy of rural swains (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 61v
Come, lay by your cares and then hang up your sorrow MS Eng 540
Come learn by this, ye bachelors MS Eng 1038.1, 40v
Come leave off your tittle tattle (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 33
Come, Leila, fill the goblet up MS Keats 3.13, i, 27
Come, let us join a joyful tune Autograph file, W: Isaac Watts, 13
Come let us rejoice, merry boys, at his fall MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 25v
Come, let us view the hosts above MS Eng 614, 43
Come listen to me, I'll tell some news MS Eng 629, 109v
Come listen to my merry strains MS Eng 1471, vii, 181v
Come listen ye tories and jacobites now Autograph file, D: John Digmore, 2
Come listen, young lovers, and you'll find MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 134v
Come, listen young lovers awhile and you'll find MS Eng 895, 16v
Come, live with me and be my love MS Eng 966.3, p. 74; MS Eng 966.1, 32; MS Eng 966.5, 153"; MS Eng 626, 68"; MS Eng 1038.1, 54v 55, 2v; MS Eng 1490, 81v; MS Eng 1470, 1, 25v
Come, Lord, from above MS Eng 616, ii, 48v
Come, Lord, the drooping sinner cheer MS Eng 616, ii, 47
Come, love, let us join MS Eng 612, ii, 90v
Come, love, lets walk into the spring MS Eng 628, 166v
Come, love we God of might is most MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 35v
Come, madam, come; all rest my powers defy MS Eng 966.3, 43; MS Eng 966.1, 18; MS Eng 966.5, 66; MS Eng 966.4, 144; MS Eng 686, 35v
Come mourn, come mourn with me MS Eng 895, 40v; MS Eng 1471, vi, 36
Come, my Cordelia, lets not leese MS Eng 645, 63v
Come, my dear Molly, and sit down by me MS Eng 1471, v, 18
Come, my lads, with souls befitting MS Eng 834, folder 13
Come, my Phillis, let us improve MS Eng 808 (8), 93
Come, my soul, thy suit prepare MS Eng 616, ii, 40v
Come nobles and gentlemen and listen all MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 197v
Come, O thou traveller unknown MS Eng 630, 32v
Come on, and seize the trembling fair MS Thr 198, folder 90
Come on, good fellows, make an end MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 144
Come on, jolly lads, to the drum head repair MS Thr 198, folder 6
Come, on my knee, love, take thy seat MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 46; MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 47
Come on, ye critics, find one fault who dare MS Eng 624, 44
Comw on, you critics, find one fault who dares MS Eng 636F, 130v
Come, painter, spread the canvas wide and fair MS Eng 629, 97
Come, prithee, leave this reading; let me hear MS Eng 159, 24v
Come riddle my riddle, dear mother, he says MS Am 2349, xxiii, 337
Come, Roger and Nell, come, Simkin and Bell MS Eng 895, 78
Come, Rosalind, O come and see MS Eng 895, 37v
Come, Saviour, Jesu, from above MS Eng 614, 103; MS Eng 614, 119v
Come, says Aaron unto Moses MS Eng 586, 246v
Come, see who can catch me MS Eng 895, 69
Come, smiling angel, Patience, from thy seat (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 8v
Come, sweet companion of each mournful hour MS Eng 926, 14v
Come, take up your burden, you dogs, and away MS Eng 512, 82v
Come taste my friend! the joys retirement brings (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 107v
Come then, my friend, my Genius come along MS Eng 233.1, 8
Come, then, oh, come, ere winter wakes to pour (incomplete) MS Eng 731, folder 126
Come, thou poet, free and brown MS Keats 4.7.1
Come we shepherds who have seen MS Eng 631, 47; MS Eng 631, 53
Come, with our voices let us war MS Eng 626, 81
Come, ye graces, come away MS Eng 785, 15v
Come ye hither, all whose taste MS Eng 631, 35v
Come, ye lovers of peace, who are said to have sold MS Eng 629, 84
Come, ye swarms of thoughts, and bring MS Eng 626, 13v
Come, ye weary sinners, come MS Eng 614, 88v
Come, you lusty northern lads MS Eng 862, 51
Come, young men and maids MS Eng 895, 32v
Come, youthful muse, who erst in college dark MS Am 715 (176), 1; MS Am 715 (176), 1
Comin' by the kirk. gawn by the steeple MS Eng 1497, ii, 125
Coming a tender girl from school MS Eng 629, 33
Commerce! thou mad'st the stars thy pilot's boast MS Am 1369, 13v
Commit thou all thy griefs MS Eng 614, 121
Compassion in the world again is bred MS Eng 966.5, 171v; MS Eng 966.4, 217; MS Eng 966.2, 28v
Compassionate Bridegroom, my shepherd and friend MS Eng 616, ii, 39v
Compound for sins they are inclined to (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 16
Compounds are made of many things we know MS Eng 1015, 122v
Concealed beneath the underworld (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xviii, p. 27
Condemned to hope's delusive mine MS Eng 926, 55
Confined to sit in silence, here I waste (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 34
Conqueror, Deliverer, Friend of human-kind MS Eng 265.2, folder 9
Conrad! Albert! help, help, what can I do (incomplete) MS Keats 2.24.3
Conrad! what tidings? Good, if I may guess (incomplete) MS Keats 2.24.1
Conscience in Sandwich Haven once was drowned MS Eng 699, 27v
Conscience, thou terror of irresolute minds (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 53v
Conscience to all men does appear (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 38v
Conscience, what art thou? thou tremendous power (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 96
Consider, gracious prince, and you, my lords (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 102v
Consider who must drink that drink, and then MS Eng 1501, 5v
Conspicuous wouldst thou be? to many known MS Eng 614, 99
Constables and beadles both (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 80
[C]onstantinopolum Relics whar he fand (incomplete) MS Eng 1032, 1v
Contemplate when the sun declines MS Keats 3.13, i, 6
Content (my companion of late) MS Eng 676F, 41v
Contentment, parent of delight (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 120v
Content's a kingdom where the soul dilates MS Eng 614, 74v
Continual toil and labor is not best MS Typ 14, 50
Cook-Laurel would needs have the devil his guest MS Eng 540
Cope loves a Monk, Monk loves a Cope again MS Eng 645, 95v
Cope sent a challenge frae Dunbar MS Eng 1497, i, 26v
Corinna, you infect my heart MS Eng 602F, 65v
Corne swore his wife no fellow had; yet sped MS Eng 228, 26v
Corporal Kill-sin Cantaway MS Eng 1132, 4
Corpses are cold in the tomb MS Eng 822, 2v of first MS; *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 48v
Cost on the dead, 'tis folly to bestow MS Eng 614, 100
Cosway, Frazer and Baldwin of Egypt's lake MS Eng 1167, 19; MS Eng 889, 12
Could but our tempers move like this machine MS Eng 680, 14; MS Eng 555, 20
Could Grecian masters from the shades return MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 37v
Could I but unthink the thought (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Could my Clidamira! you MS Am 1919, 40v
Could not the angel's charge (weak woman) turn MS Eng 159, 20
Could Samson e'er have been so strong MS Eng 645, 57
Could such a tyrant E'er be the father of a queen, adorn'd (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 41v
Could we judge here, most virtuous madam, then MS Eng 631, 94
Could you a virgin's beauty but regain (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 97
Could youth, could innocence, could virtue save MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), 62
Courage, my lord. Let not your fancy scan MS Eng 645, 7v
Count not on hopeWe never can take leave, my friend, of life (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 100v
Courts have their harlotry and vices (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 74
Coward death, thy Stygian dart MS Eng 703, 39
Cowden Nelsey, cowden Nelsey MS Eng 1497, ii, 132
Coxton has but ae hoggie MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 102
Coy Celia, dost thou see MS Eng 626, 65
Cr____ loves artists as he loves his meat MS Eng 1167, 15; MS Eng 889, 8
Creator spirit, by whose aid MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 48v
Creature so strange, so wretched one as I MS Eng 628, 160v
Critics avaunt, for you are fish of prey (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 49v
Cromek loves artists as he loves his meat MS Eng 1167, 77
Crowded on his mind In swift succession, numberless; but still (incomplete) MS Eng 947.8, Critique of poems...Watts
Crown me a cheerful goblet, while I pray MS Eng 601.66, 10
Cruel since that thou dost not fear the curse MS Eng 966.5, 80v; MS Eng 966.2, 11
Cruel, since thou dost fear the curse MS Eng 686, 51v
Cry a reward to him who shall first bring (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 70
Crystalline Brother of the Belt of Heaven (incomplete) MS Keats 3.3, p. 52
[___]cte brede but a qu[___] Tua hennes at anes he[___]tt wase he MS Eng 1032, 1
Cuckolds and misers here are plenty (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 82v
Cullies from Bath and Tunbridge now repair MS Eng 611, ii, 77v
Culloden is lost! and the clans are away MS Am 2349, ii, p. 49
Cupid, although a child's, so strong MS Eng 645, 31
Cupid, that sly, that artful boy MS Eng 926, 32v
Cupid, wheresoe'er thou be MS Eng 785, 44v
Cupid, youthful god of love MS Am 1919, 20v
Curb that impetuous tongue, nor rashly vain (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 60
Curs'd be those dull, unpointed, doggerel rhymes MS Eng 633, 45; MS Eng 585, 222
Curse on the day when thou wast born (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 83
Curse on the sound! the temple and the temple MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 31
Curse on those critics, ignorant and vain MS Eng 633, 11v; MS Eng 585, 65
Curst be the hand that shot the shot (incomplete) MS Am 2349, i, p. 125
Custom, alas! does partial prove MS Eng 629, 22v
Custom at masquerades agrees MS Eng 611, ii, 13v
Cut off my head and singular I act MS Eng 569.67, 85
Cut off my head and singulars act MS Eng 569.67, 83
D
Dame Jane, a sprightly nun, and gay MS Eng 1491 (3), 79v
Dame Nature one day in a comical mood MS Thr 198, folder 56
Dame Nature, skillful grown by practice long MS Eng 703, 17v
Dame Winefruit in haste made a vow to be chaste MS Eng 686, 138
Damn that opinion which will not allow MS Eng 585, 216v; MS Eng 633, 44v
Damn with faint praise, assent with civil leer (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 78v
Damon languished at my feet (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 95v
Damon my beauty doth adore MS Eng 626, 64v
Damon, that author of so great renown MS Eng 585, 185v; MS Eng 633, 37
Damon, why will you die for love MS Eng 895, 51
Dance not, sing not, fiddle not, flute not MS Keats 3.13, ii, 39v
Dance round his Europe and again excite (incomplete) MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), 52
Danger has been my mistress; death, I've met (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 5
Dark as that man who at Mohammed's door MS Eng 265.2, folder 4
Dark o'er the desert waste the low'ring clouds MS Eng 926, 16
Darwent! what scenes thy wandering waves behold (incomplete) MS Am 2349, v, p. 179
David ne'er touch'd the hark like thee MS Eng 1502 (3), 118v
Davie Gordon in Kirktown MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 197v
Days of my youth! ye have glided away MS Keats 3.13, i, 27v
Dead be my heart to all below Autograph file, W: Isaac Watts, 18v
Dead is the summer's flowery pride (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 35v
Dead must his heart be, when the blooming year MS Eng 1461, 69
Deaf to reproach I boldly stray MS Eng 623
Deal healy wi' me, Robie MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 116
Dear bard, your verses on our senses creep MS Eng 1502 (3), 114
Dear Barton I vow MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 24
Dear Betsy, the joy of my eyes MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 41
Dear, blessed child, who is so stayed and bent (incomplete) MS Typ 49, 4
Dear brother, or sir, for I'm sure we are kin MS Eng 623
Dear Caleb, what the devil ails ye MS Eng 629, 106v
Dear Charles, I've thought you even from a child MS Eng 926, 42
Dear Charlotte, how awkward life seems without thee MS Eng 926, 56
Dear Chloe, while the busy crowd (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 137
Dear Chloe, while thus beyond measure MS Eng 895, 75v
Dear Christ, my poor and pensive breast MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 160
Dear Colin prevent my warm blushes MS Eng 512, 81v
Dear friend, have ye heard the fantastical chimes MS Eng 629, 104v
Dear friend, I fain would try once more MS Eng 633, 33; MS Eng 585, 165v
Dear friends, if you'll be ruled by me MS Eng 612, iii, 80
Dear, give me a thousand kisses MS Eng 626, 19
Dear, I to thee this diamond commend MS Eng 121, 2
Dear John, if you are not belied EC7. Ox250.702p (originally ML 15.2F), item 4
Dear Kitty! now my counsel take MS Eng 612, ii, 74
Dear lad, wha' linkan o'er the lee MS Eng 793, 1
Dear love, continue nice and chaste MS Eng 966.3, p. 119; MS Eng 966.7, 21; MS Eng 966.5, 154v; MS Eng 966.4, 212v
Dear love, for nothing less than thee MS Eng 966.3, 69; MS Eng 966.1, 26v; MS Eng 966.5, 137v; MS Eng 966.4, 189v
Dear Lucy, why think I'm deceiving MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 46; MS Eng 1260 folder 47
Dear Madam! oh, how great the pity MS Eng 612, ii, 13v
Dear maid! no prattler at a mother's knee (incomplete) MS Eng 947, A.L.s. to Allsop
Dear Mirtillo, fair and bright MS Eng 895, 38
Dear Mrs. Anne, I'm certain you'll find true MS Eng 612, iii, 93
Dear mistress, wheresoever you do rest MS Eng 626, 2v
Dear mother, dear mother, the church is cold MS Eng 1167, 53; MS Eng 1167, 75
Dear offspring of my thoughtless years MS Eng 926, 1
Dear Reynolds, as last night I lay in bed MS Keats 3.2, 65
Dear, rip my heart and see MS Eng 626, 2
Dear Savior, oh! what ails this heart MS Eng 584, 40
Dear sir, as you are MS Eng 692, 32
Dear sir, I acknowledge I'm really a fash MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 223
Dear sir, not for your name to tunes will sound MS Eng 228, 26
Dear son, What is it? By your father's love I sue (incomplete) MS Keats 2.24.7, 1
Dear, throw that flattering glass away MS Eng 626, 2
Dear Tommy, talk not of the seas MS Eng 895, 82
Dearest, I'm convinced: thou art a gem (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 29v
Dearest, I'm dying! bend thee down MS Am 988, 14v
Dearest Mira, since thou hast MS Eng 626, 23
Death and this man were long at a stand MS Eng 686, 12; MS Eng 686, 54
Death, be not proud, though some have called thee MS Eng 966.3, 98; MS Eng 966.5, 19v; MS Eng 966.5, 86; MS Eng 966.4, 84v
Death came unto a usurer MS Eng 247.5, 11
Death doing us a turban'd masquerade (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 33
Death ends both scorn and pride (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 33
Death heretofore the look'd for close MS Eng 785, 45
Death I recant and say, unsaid by me MS Eng 966.3, 26v; MS Eng 966.1, 43; MS Eng 966.5, 85; MS Eng 966.4, 138v
Death in the shape of a thin poet's come MS Eng 540
Death is a hero, whose relief is sure (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 53v
Death is the last of ills that he can do (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 27
Death on a solemn night of state MS Eng 1038.2, 51v
Death once a tyrant, now a conquered slave MS Eng 623
Death shant have power our souls to disunite (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 25v
Death, thou art welcome; come whene'er thou wilt MS Eng 611, iii, 30
Death throws me here beneath this stone MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 25
Death, to all troubles, gives a gentle end (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 21v
Death we should prize as the best gift of nature (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 4
Death! well, and what is Death, hoary philosophers (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 54
Death, who cannot change prerogatives with thee MS Eng 1107, folder 5
Deceit to secrecy confin'd (incomplete) MS Eng 1167, 54
Deep from within she seems half way (incomplete) EC. C 6795.817s (c) (formerly 19478.65), p. 18
Deep in a desert-vale, a palace frowns (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 7
Deep in an unctious vale twixt swelling hills MS Eng 636F, 20v
Deep in the shady sadness of a vale MS Keats 3.2, 79; MS Keats 3.1, 22
Deep lamenting loss of treasure MS Eng 1495, 10v
Deferor tempestas hospes quo me cunque rapit MS Eng 265.1, folder 14
Deign at my hands this crown of prayer and praise MS Eng 966.3, 95; MS Eng 966.7, 53v; MS Eng 966.5, 14v
Deign at my hands this crown of praise and prayer MS Eng 966.4, 80
Delicate hands and heads will never appear MS Eng 1167, 24; MS Eng 889, 17
Delights so sweet the spring and grottos give (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 4
Deliver us through thy descent MS Eng 966.4, 87v
Deluded mortal, turn and view thy store MS Eng 680, 45
Deluded mortals, whom the great MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 70
[Departed ages] shedding where he flew *EC8. W8915.838s, p. 301
Depending on no cultivator's care (incomplete) MS Eng 569.67, 23
Depending seemingly on air MS Eng 612, ii, 77
Descended from an ancient line MS Eng 640, 15
Desire to have doth make us much endure MS Typ 14, 10v
Despair is all folly: hence melancholy MS Eng 1038.1, 3
Despair leads to battle, no courage so great MS Eng 1038.1, 8v
Despairing beside a clear stream MS Eng 512, 43v
Desponding Phillis was endued (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 97
Destruction's Empire shall no longer last (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 99v
Diana, if your eyes can look so low MS Eng 703, 35
Dick Melvin, Dick Melvin, now since ye are gone MS Eng 1491 (3), 52
Did ancient Socrates his fame advance MS Eng 686, 21
Did Ben now live, how would he fret and rage MS Eng 674, 7v
Did but thy dowry answer thy desert MS Eng 702, 5
Dis Caelia's person and her mind agree MS Eng 629, 22
Did Jesus teach doubt? or did he MS Eng 1167, 25; MS Eng 889, 18
Did they add to the pains they've endured ten times more (incomplete) MS Thr 198, folder 27
Did they together testify of time (incomplete) MS Eng 327 (4), p. 5
Did ye ever hear o' guid Earl o' Bran MS Eng 1470, 61
Did ye ever hear of a loyal Scot MS Am 2349, i, p. 103; MS Eng 1471, i, 26
Did ye ever travel 'twixt Berwick and Lyne MS Eng 1471, i, 44
Did ye see e'er a shepherd, ye nymphs, pass this way MS Eng 895, 10v
Did you ever hear of a royal Scot MS Eng 1497, ii, 52v; MS Am 2349, i, 105
Did you hear of Sir James the Rose MS Eng 862, 65v
Didst thou, O magistrate, see MS Eng 265.1, folder 5
Didst thou the milk of some fierce tigress suck MS Eng 611, iii, 25
Dinna ask me gin I love thee MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 102v
Discolor'd, pale, as bastard pearl (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 61
Discord and plots which have undone our age MS Eng 584, 38v
Disdainful Chlona, canst thou destrise MS Eng 808 (8), 68
Disease and sin with wild unmanly rhyme MS Eng 228, 2-leaf sheet
Disgraced, undone, forlorn, made Fortune's sport MS Eng 629, 28
Dissolved in sleep, one silent night I lay MS Eng 676F, 42
Distended with the waters in 'em pent (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 101
Distill me this water MS Eng 1015, 17
Distrust and darkness of a future state MS Eng 602F, 4
Divideand partthe severed world in two (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 101v
Divide my times, and rate my wretched labors MS Eng 1494, 18
Divine command long since did dedicate MS Eng 623
Divine S. John to Patmos Ile exiled MS Typ 49, 130
Divinely has blest Providence design'd (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 67v
Do anything but love; or, if thou lovest MS Am 988, 17v
Do but be in my house as busy as a bee (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Do but consider this small dust MS Eng 966.7, 32; MS Eng 966.5, 140v; MS Eng 966.2, 5v"; MS Eng 626, 74
Do, happy birds, my suit renew MS Eng 808 (8), 64
Do I regret the past (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 58v
Do not fright me, gentle Dobbin MS Eng 1323, 19
Do not, most fragrant earl, disclaim MS Eng 606, 85
Do the fresh streams pay tribute to the seas MS Eng 645, 77
Do they themselves who undertake for hire (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 28
Do ye forget the blows, the buffets vile (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 16
Do you see this rope's end MS Thr 198, folder 90
Do you see yon little boy (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xviii, p. 27
Do you see yon little boy playing with the ball (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xviii, p. 31
Doctissime Apollo Autograph file, D: John Digmore, 2
Doctor, your epigram is true MS Eng 569.63, 2v
Does a monarch reside in that gingerbread toy MS Keats 3.4, 5
Does Halsted wear its native face MS Eng 926, 39
Does lov'd Emilia trembling wait her doom (incomplete) MS Am 2349, v, p. 177
Does not the hen call in his light, and day MS Eng 631, 107
Dolefu' rings the bell o' rain MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 166v
Donald Cooper comes at e'en MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 171
Donne, the delight of Phoebus and each muse MS Eng 966.2, 1
Doomed, as I am, in solitude to waste (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 30
Doon Decside rade Inveray whistling and playing MS Am 2349, i, p. 67
Dorinda and her spouse were joined MS Eng 569.65, 4v
Dorset no gentle nymph can find MS Eng 633, 12v; MS Eng 585, 70v
Dost thou think I have forgot my valiant leader (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 9
Dost thou desire a good man to be styled MS Eng 614, 98
Dost thou inquire what thou shouldst chiefly shun MS Eng 623
Dost thou know what reputation is (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 5
Doth G. write? surely there's somewhat in't MS Eng 699, 27
Dot'st thou on wealth, thou seemst by heaven decry'd MS Eng 614, 102v
Down by a crystal river side MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 171v; MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 228v
Down by a river side MS Am 2349, ii, p. 84
Down by this smooth stream's wandering side MS Eng 1490, 79
Down by yon crystal river side MS Eng 1491 (3), 20
Down by yon fallow land MS Eng 1471, v, 22
Down, down, my heart, and do not swell MS Eng 703, 15
Down, down, thou fair infectious charm of beauty (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 8
Down ffrom hevyn ffor alle his deyite (incomplete) MS Eng 752, 1; MS Eng 752, 1
Down in a garden sat my dearest love MS Eng 686, 47v
Down in yon garden sweet and gay MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 86v
Down in yon meadow a couple did tarry MS Eng 1497, i, 35
Down in yonder garden gay MS Am 2349, xxi, 64; MS Am 2349, xxix, 1033
Draw hither a while my little dear thing MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 202